<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Julia Website]]></title><description><![CDATA[Obsidian digital garden]]></description><link>http://github.com/dylang/node-rss</link><image><url>lib\media\favicon.png</url><title>Julia Website</title><link></link></image><generator>Webpage HTML Export plugin for Obsidian</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2024 12:27:25 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="lib\rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2024 12:27:24 GMT</pubDate><ttl>60</ttl><dc:creator></dc:creator><item><title><![CDATA[Education]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>M.S. in Computer Science from the <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://www.st-andrews.ac.uk/" rel="noopener" class="external-link" href="https://www.st-andrews.ac.uk/" target="_blank">University of St. Andrews</a> (Scotland) Expected 2025<br>B.S. with Honors in Data Analytics from <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://www.osu.edu/" rel="noopener" class="external-link" href="https://www.osu.edu/" target="_blank">The Ohio State University</a> (USA) 2024<br>
Coursework:<br>
Computer Science: Java software composition and development, C, x86-64 assembly language, C++, Python, SQL, UX UI Design, Data Management in the Cloud, Data Mining
Statistics: Probability and Statistical Inference for Data Analysis, Statistical Modeling for Discovery 1-3, Statistical Learning, Bayesian Statistics

Math: Honors Mathematical Analysis, Linear Algebra, Differential Equations, Calculus 1-3, Scientific Computing

Integrated Systems Engineering: Systems Modeling and Optimization for Analytics, Visual Analytics and Sensemaking, Resilience Engineering
Copy
]]></description><link>education.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Education.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2024 12:09:51 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Julia Dreiling]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Julia Dreiling is a multi-disciplinary data scientist who has worked for Berkeley Labs, Dell Technologies, and the US Veterans Affairs Hospital on automation and machine learning <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Projects and Presentations" data-href="Projects and Presentations" href="\projects-and-presentations.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">projects</a>. She <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Education" data-href="Education" href="\education.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">studied</a> Data Analytics at The Ohio State University and is currently pursing her Masters in Computer Science at the University of St. Andrews in Scotland. She is <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Research Interests" data-href="Research Interests" href="\research-interests.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">interested</a> in cognitive systems and human computer interaction research, particularly projects that focus on human impact. She has professional experience with Python, SQL, PowerBi, and Github. In her <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Personal" data-href="Personal" href="\personal.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">free time</a> Julia enjoys playing and filming ultimate frisbee and spending time with her one-eyed cat <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Personal" data-href="Personal" href="\personal.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Odin</a>. <br><a data-href="Resume" href="\Resume" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Resume</a><br>
<a data-href="CV" href="\CV" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">CV</a><br>
<a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://github.com/jmdreiling" rel="noopener" class="external-link" href="https://github.com/jmdreiling" target="_blank">Github</a><br>Contact Information<br>
<a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="mailto:jmcd1@st-andrews.ac.uk" rel="noopener" class="external-link" href="mailto:jmcd1@st-andrews.ac.uk" target="_blank">jmcd1@st-andrews.ac.uk</a><br>
<a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="mailto:Julia.Dreiling@outlook.com" rel="noopener" class="external-link" href="mailto:Julia.Dreiling@outlook.com" target="_blank">Julia.Dreiling@outlook.com</a><br>This website was created with GitHub, Obsidian, and <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://github.com/KosmosisDire" rel="noopener" class="external-link" href="https://github.com/KosmosisDire" target="_blank">Nathan George</a>'s   <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://github.com/KosmosisDire/obsidian-webpage-export" rel="noopener" class="external-link" href="https://github.com/KosmosisDire/obsidian-webpage-export" target="_blank">Obsidian to HTML plug in</a>. ]]></description><link>julia-dreiling.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Julia Dreiling.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2024 12:24:15 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Personal]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>My best friend and constant Zoom call menace, Odin is a one-eyed cat who adores chattering at birds, food, and sleeping in whatever soft corner he can snuggle himself into. He is very friendly and sociable and easily won over by treats and pets.<br><img alt="IMG_0260.jpg" src="\images\img_0260.jpg"><br><br>Aside from Data Science and Human Factors, Ultimate Frisbee might be my only other true love. I spend her free time photographing and filming ultimate when I can't play due to chronic knee injury and spent my high school and undergraduate years playing for various school and club teams. I also dabble in some drone filming if the weather is clear enough. I am always happy to chat about the ultimate scene or to toss around in a free moment.<br>Some of my favorite photos<br>
<img alt="IMG_1528-2.jpg" src="\images\img_1528-2.jpg"><br>
<img alt="IMG_6688.jpg" src="\images\img_6688.jpg"><img alt="IMG_8118.jpg" src="\images\img_8118.jpg">]]></description><link>personal.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Personal.md</guid><pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 13:28:45 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="images\img_0260.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;images\img_0260.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Projects]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br><br>June - August 2024<br>
I worked for the Cognitive Systems Engineering Lab (CSEL) at The Ohio State University editing video lectures by Dr. David Woods to produce accessible introductory resilience engineering education materials. This included:<br>
<br>editing hours of footage
<br>basic sound cleanup and color correction
<br>creating flexible and novel graphics to aid understanding
<br>animating key concepts
<br>publishing approved videos to the CSEL YouTube Channel<br>
From there I built out a graphical navigation website to explore different concepts through the videos as well as two subpages for the CSEL home website. I developed a much deeper understanding of the field of Resilience Engineering (RE) along with my Adobe Suite Skills. I am deeply committed to producing accessible and educational RE content as I believe our systems need to be developed no longer with just basic fail-safes in mind, but with Resilience in the forefront of our design decisions.
<br><br>October 2022 - June 2024<br>
Throughout my third and fourth year at Ohio State, I worked on the calibration and filter optimization system for Berkeley labs' GRETA project under the guidance of Dr. Heather Crawford and Dr. Marco Salathe. <br>Because I am not an expert in low level nuclear physics, I spent much of my first year researching the parameter space of the GRETA detector and learning about signal filter shaping parameters and methods. Then in the summer of 2023, I moved out to Berkeley for a few months to participate in the US Department of Energy's  Summer Undergraduate Laboratory Internship (SULI) program to build the initial optimization pipeline for GRETA’s detectors. After my SULI experience wrapped up, I continued working remotely to refine the pipeline and expand it's capacity beyond just the crystal cores the initial system was based on. During this time I attended the 2023 Fall Meeting of APS DNP and JPS in Hawaii where I presented my pipeline work at the CEU poster session and visited Michigan State's Facility for Rare Isotope Beams in January 2024 to assist with an experiment using GRETINA, the predecessor to GRETA.  I finalized my work in May 2024 and spent June writing extensive documentation for future users and programmers.<br>During this time I developed skills in:<br>
<br>Signal Processing
<br>Basics of Low-Level Nuclear Physics
<br>Becquerel Python Package
<br>NLOpt Python Package
<br>PyEPICS Python Package
<br>Technical Writing
<br>Detailed Documentation
<br><br>January - April 2024<br>
In my final semester of my Senior year at The Ohio State University I worked on a dashboard  for Honda Motor Co.'s HR department to help them visualize and analyze key data about their employees and company-wide metrics. I worked in joint with my classmate Eric Paquin and was supervised by Dr. Thomas Metzger. I focused on the front-end user interface and worked directly with the client to fulfill their visions for the dashboard.<br>
Throughout this project I gained skills in:<br>
<br>PowerBI
<br>Client Communications
<br>Project Management and Development Timelines
<br><br>June - August 2022<br>
In the Summer of 2022, I was lucky enough to intern with Dell Technologies at their headquarters in Austin, Texas. During this internship I worked with the Quality Intelligence team to build an automated service request classifier that processed over 1.5 million entries to pinpoint areas of product improvement for quality engineers. I learned a lot from working with senior software engineers in a team that spanned both the Client Solutions Group and the Infrastructure Solutions Group. At the end of my internship I presented my insights on my work to a panel of managers and vice presidents and implemented my classifier within the Quality Intelligence dashboard.<br>
Throughout this internship I developed expertise in:<br>
<br>Common NLP Techniques
<br>Data Cleaning
<br>Data Labelling
<br>SQL
<br>Python
<br><br>June - August 2021<br>
My first true dive into data science was in the summer between my freshman and sophomore year when I interned under Dr. Andrew Chou in Houston, Texas. In this internship I used Python to clean streptococcus data for feature selection and tokenization and then I put that data through various out of the box machine learning algorithms to help with the overall project of automating the classification of clinical records for the VA hospital system. ##While my code didn't make it into production## , this initial exploration of NLP ignited my passion for code, scientific discovery, and human-centered data science.<br><br>At the 2023 Fall Meeting of the Division of Nuclear Physics of the American Physical Society and the Physical Society of Japan, in Waikoloa, Hawaii, I presented a poster on Gamma-Ray Energy Tracking Array (GRETA) Filter Parameter Optimization and Calibration at the CEU (Conference Experience for Undergraduates) poster session on November 29th, 2023. This presentation was a more developed iteration of my SULI poster and research.<br>At the SULI Summer 2023 Virtual Poster Presentation, I presented a poster on Gamma-Ray Energy Tracking Array (GRETA) Filter Parameter Optimization and Calibration on August 9th, 2023]]></description><link>projects-and-presentations.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects and Presentations.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2024 12:25:38 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>